A Guide to the Papers of Thomas Law, 1803-1834
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- [Thomas Law] to his nephew, [Charles Rumbold] 18[34] Feb 12, 2p frag
  " ... how miserably selfish my Br[other George] is ... [while I was in England he] refused to be my security - thus he injured my credit ... He wants to injure my Character by calling me a gambler - now in all my life I never better more than a dollar at Whist. I have it is true a great discovery ... to break the plundering Companies ... I told [Isaac] Ward the secret & he would have played & was to advance half ... had I succeeded I should have gloried in breaking the plunderers. The truth is George Law is a selfish ... "
- Thomas Law to his nephew, Charles Rumbold N.D., 2p w/addr
  " ... the occasion compels me to shew the effects of my System, at a Crisis, when we are receiving unwellcome intelligence from the Northwest ... I hope you are an advocate for the Loan Company, in imitation of the Monte de la piete ... in America my Muse aided me to depict the situation of Widows whose Husbands had a long voyage at Sea, & who were obliged to pledge ... with pawnbrokers. This Company will be a truly charitable useful institution ... "
- Thomas Law to his nephew, Charles Rumbold N.D., 1p w/addr
  " ... Shew the enclosed to any financier. Having finished my India matters ... attending to others ...
  Enclosed manuscript: "
- "A suggestion for the rapid advancement of Ireland" N.D., 7p
- Thomas Law to his nephew, Charles Rumbold [written while in England] N.D., 3p w/addr
  " ... I send you the 4th volume of Veseys report in which you will see how shamefully I was treated ... After my departure from India ... I had not a fortune after these cruel deductions to live like others in England, I therefore went to america ... On my arrival here, I found my System checked & a ruinous one preferred ... I now send you an addendum - the opinions of the Directors & the minutes of the revered Cornwallis merit your perusal as a Member of Parliament ... "
- Thomas Law to Isaac Ward N.D., 1p
  " ... Should any accident happen to me ... I hereby authorize Mr William Blane ... to receive the principal I have advanced & my half of the profits ... "
- manuscript by [Thomas Law] N.D., 3p
  ""Soliloquy of one of the holy alliance" Confound the British who bold doctrines spread Making the crown sit heavy on my head ... Our friend his Catholic Majesty, from Spain For promis'd succor urges us in vain ... The throne & Church most firmly had combin'd T'arrest the dangerous progress of mans mind ... No separation we can now create United this Great Britain doubly great ... "
- manuscript by [Thomas Law] N.D., 6p
  ""Loose thoughts on the Irish Question" ... IN vain it is argued that Superstition has declined always as knowledge advanced, & that Bigotry has uniformly dimished as oppression relaxed ... "
- "Memoranda for Charles Rumbold, Esq." by Thomas Law [incomplete] N.D., 3p
  "Mentions conditions in Mexico, economic matters, and [Simon] Bolivar. "
- Thomas Law to Mrs. [James] Madison [written in third person] N.D., 1p w/addr
  "Presents Mr. Bonchard's model of a mausoleum for [George] Washington. "
- Thomas Law to Mrs. [James] Madison [written in third person] N.D., 1p
  "Invites her to solicit subscribers to a "translation" of Le Sages' maps. "
- Thomas Law to Mrs. [James] Madison N.D., 1p
  "Reports on the distribution of tickets. "